RIEFAT DOLLIE

Mobile: +2782

461 5852

assertrd@webmail.

CO.Za

Licanca

Male ID: Upon Request Age 38 Code 08 Drivers

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

I am an IT / Business professional currently employed for a financial technology company. I have gained invaluable experience working for companies in the private sector such as private capital markets, short term loans, telecommunications, investment management, prepayment electricity solutions and ecommerce and point of sale.

Working in the IT industry for the past 17 years, I have gained experience in Quality Assurance such as Test Automation, Manual Testing, Software development as well as Business Analysis. I have an innate talent for leveraging technology along with my skillset to resolve complex issues and eliminate inefficiencies. I have worked on projects from inception to completion using the Agile and the Waterfall methodology. As part of my technical skillset I have used Selenium C#, API Testing, extensive experience in SQL. I have been a Testing for more than 10 years.

I am comfortable working under pressure yet maintaining my enthusiasm and focus while working on projects. I have been promoted to a lead position in two companies, providing guidance to junior team members and managing project deliverables. I am highly motivated with a growth mindset and continuously making an effort to develop my skillset.

TRAINING AND CERTIFICATIONS COMPLETED

CSPO : Certified Scrum Product Owner (Agile),

Scrum Alliance

ISEB Foundation : Certified Test Analyst, British Computer Society
ISTQB Advanced Core : Advanced Problem Solving and Testing,

iLab

Agile Training: iLab, FTi

Certified Automation Tester: Automation in Worksoft Certify, SQIM

QUALIFICATIONS / EDUCATION DETAILS

SECONDARY EDUCATION

Institution : Harold Cressy High School

Grade : Matric

Subjects : English, Afrikaans, Mathematics, Technical

Drawings, Biology,

Economics

TERTIARY EDUCATION

Institution : CTi Education Group

Modules : Structured Programming & Relational Database

Design

Qualification : **Diploma**, Information Technology

2019

Institution : Cape Peninsula University of Technology
Modules : Business Analysis & Software development
Qualification : National Diploma, Information Technology

Institution : Faculty Training Institute (FTi)

Module : Business Analysis

Qualification : Advanced Business Analysis Diploma,

Advanced Training

Institution : Cape Peninsula University of Technology

(Part Time)

Started : 2018

Expected: 2020

Qualification : BTech, Information & Technology

Management

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Senior Engineer - Automation

Name of Company : iLab

Type of Company : Consulting for Telecoms
Period : November 2019 - Current

Product Build : Project CCS

Implementing a Hybrid framework for a Telecoms Billing System

- Using Selenium WebDiver plugin for Java
- TestNG
- Information gathering and indentifying automation requirements
- Analyzing data to be used for automation
- Assessing manual regression test base and providing estimates for automated deliverables
- Assessing which test cases should be automated and defining the scope for automation
- Conducting risk analysis and communicating risk levels to a team of manual test engineers
- Facilitating and conducting demos of the automation suite to the team
- Providing test coverage in the form of reporting to the team
- Intellij, SOAPUI

Senior Engineer - Automation

Name of Company : iLab

Type of Company : Consulting for Retail

Period: April 2019 - November 2019

Product Build : Project Fox

- Completed and implemented an Automation framework for the SAP ERP system using UFT
- Working closely with BA's and FA's
- Conducting extensive analysis based on the data received from the BI team
- Responsible for delivering 40 story points per week
- Demos conducted on a weekly basis to client
- Constructing functions to control business logic
- Adopting modular program design standards
- Peer reviews

- Data and Key-word driven approach and conducting extensive analysis on data flow
- VB Script using the UFT Framework for automating the SAP workflows
- Constructing of functions for complex business rules
- TestNG for reporting results to be extracted after each execution for management review
- Advanced SQL in own capacity trying to meet performance expectations
- Selenium Web Driver
- Scripting automated tests for web
- Scripting automated test for API's
- Tools Swagger, Postman, Eclipse IDE, GIT, Bitbucket, QC

Strategic Project

SAP – Retail Promotion Business Process was fully automated and signed off. My intention for phase two of this project was to optimize the automation regression suite by designing and implementing a relational database for execution due to the limitation of UFT and excel.

TECHNICAL BUSINESS ANALYST

Name of Company : Black Swan Data

Type of Company : Avionics

Period: DEC 2018 - March 2019

Product Build : Design

- Liaising with business and head of development to elicit business requirements
- Gathering requirements for Proof Of Concept
- Conducting refinements with management
- Documenting of business requirements using annoted models
- Liaising between Engineering and DeVops
- Working Closely with the UX design team
- Conducting investigations and impact analysis on product incidents

Lead Engineer - Product Analyst and Automation

Name of Company : Ipreo / IHS Makit

Type of Company : Global Capital Markets

Period : March 2016 - November 2018
Product Build : Fixed Income and Investor Access

- Exposed to Fixed Income trading in the financial sector working with all major Banks RBC, BAML, SocGen, JP Morgan
- Conducting Regression, complex functional and non-functional testing
- Automation in C # using selenium WebDriver for front end automation
- Backend testing of XML Api and RESTFull services
- Using advanced SQL
- Behavioural driven development by writing BDDs using the gerhken framework
- Ensuring that the Impact Analysis is complete before drafting test cases
 Refining and Reviewing of story acceptance criteria for deriving test cases
- Ensuring that the test strategy and plans are in place prior to patch releases
- Adhered to a fully agile approach on the implementation team for 1 year
- Following the Kanban approach on the product facing team for 1 year +
- Managing and reviewing of the product backlog and conducting investigations

- Responsible for determining if reported issues should take the form of change-requests
- Conducting root cause analysis for items in the product backlog
- Managing and reviewing of the product backlog and conducting investigations
- Responsible for performing gap analysis and updating of the regression test suite
- Investigating Issue Book integration points to align with the Issue Net shared platform
- Liaising with client services and investigating issues reported by clients
- Defect tracking of any issues in Jira and salesforce
- Responsible for investigating work-flows for the fixed income platform and liaising with product owners and developers and identifying improvements to workflow processes
- Conducting As-Is analysis of fixed income workflow process and mapping out the business activity
- Eliciting essential needs of project stakeholders and transforming it into requirements
- Assisting in prioritizing requirements in line with market and customer requirements
- Responsible for facilitating walkthroughs of new enhancements
- Responsible post production validation after patch releases and program increments
- Tools JMeter, Git, Fiddler, MS Visual Studio, ARC

Strategic Projects

- o Investor Access on the Buyside Portal Deal type and sales mapping functionality
- o Book building platform for fixed income XML API, Add Order Module

Senior Analyst - Testing

Name of Company : Capfin

Type of Company : Short Term Loans

Period : November 2015 - March 2016
Product Build : Fixed Income and Investor Access

- Responsible for conducting root cause analysis on the origination loan process
- Performing functional testing of new implementations
- Reviewing requirement specifications and drafting manual test cases
- Debugging stored procedures
- Using advance sql when required
- Working closely with the product owners on documenting certain workflow activities
- Regression, Functional Testing
- ALM Test Manager

Automation Analyst - Integration

Name of Company : SANLAM

Type of Company : Financial Services

Period: September 2013 - September 2015

Department : Sanlam Employee Benefits

- As a senior automation / Test engineer responsible for implementing an automation test suite for the STeP system.
- Proof of concept to motivate for purchasing of the automation tool
- Responsible for automation script execution
- Responsible for regression testing and conducting complex functional manual testing
- Responsible for scheduling and facilitating performance test and exploratory sessions
- Extensive use of SQL
- Compiling test strategies for management.
- Liaising with internal auditors and compiling test reports for auditors.
- Mediating between the development team and test team.
- Updating management on automation progress on a weekly basis
- Information gathering using the following techniques :
 - o Interviewing of internal stakeholders to elicit requirements
 - o Observations of daily work-flow processes for the STeP system
 - o Interface analysis of As-Is process model
- Stakeholder analysis in that liaising with various stakeholders to understand and document current business processes, document priorities.
- Documenting the requirements gathered during information gathering sessions.
- Translating requirements gathered into design.

Projects

o SEB Straight Through Electronic Processing

Senior Test Engineer - Analysis and Testing

Name of Company : CSG International
Type of Company : Telecommunications

Period : 23 May 2011 - 30 August 2013

Product Build : Optimized Routing

- Acting Test Lead for 6 Months
- Extensive use of SQL, Linux where necessary
- Responsible for conducting functional, non-functional and regression testing
- Testing of aggregated data with a good understanding of star-schemas a fact tables
- Responsible for compiling test summary reports for management
- Strictly adhering to testing best practices and implementing best practices
- Responsible for Package certification and release management of patches
- Using SOAP UI for API Testing
- QC ALM
- Reviewing and reworking of requirements definition for deriving test cases
- Eliciting requirements using various techniques
- Producing of mock-ups using prototypes
- Conducting document analysis of As-Is and integrated modules
- Conducting impact analysis with the developer and reviewing process flow

Business Intelligence

2019

- Deriving test cases from informational requirements for SAP Business Object Reports.
- Testing the reporting model for SAP Business Object Reports
- Analysis of data warehouse and data marts
- Testing of ETL processes for OLAP and OLTP
- Working with Star Schemas for aggregated data and Dimensional Modelling

BA

Name of Company : e-Cash System s

Type of Company : ecommerce - Online Wallet and Payment Systems

Period : 01 May 2010 - May 2011 Product Build : Systems design and analysis

- Analyzing stakeholder and business requirements through document analysis, interface analysis for As-is system modules
- Updating existing document repository for system, solution and project related information
- Create functional and technical specifications and test plans from business solutions
- Conceptual outline of the wallet model and reviewing of system components of the wallet system for Online Gaming transactions and transfers
- Documenting process flow design using UML and BPMN
- Prototyping mock-ups for client Gaming websites and Gaming payment upload systems
- Facilitating focus group session to elicit information from external stakeholders
- Facilitating scum ceremonies, review sessions
- Gather high-level requirements during workshops and reaching closure an concensus on requirements
- Conducting technical walkthrough sessions and demos to the project stakholders

Strategic Projects

- o Lobanet Payment upload system
- o ecash Wallet Asynchronous Credit Card Payments, Account registrations, Client Websites, XML Interface

Test Team Lead and Test Analyst

Name of Company : e-Cash System s

Type of Company : eCommerce - Online Wallet and Payment Systems

Period : 03 December 2007 - May 2010

Product Build : Testing and analysis

Promoted to Test Team Lead my responsibilities the included the following:

- Responsible for leading a team of 4 test analysts of which 2 were automation testers
- Responsible for performance reviews and KPIs
- Planning and scheduling all test activities relating to project including
- Responsible for conducting regular load and performance testing of Wallet System
- Conducting testing for system, integration and end to end levels for Gaming Sites
- Responsible for backend testing of XML APIS using SOAPUI and JMeter
- Conducting and guiding the operations team to assist with fail-over testing
- As the lead responsible for enforcing best practices and ensuring the test teams adheres to process standards

- Identifying the suitable test basis by exercising detailed analysis of requirement specifications.
- Liaising with business analysts, developers and solution architect to better understand impacted areas.
- Responsible for conducting security and penetration for PCI guided by COMSEC IS-RAEL
- Using technologies such as Wireshark, WebScarab and Fidler for security testing (OWASP)
- Responsible for evaluating training needs for the test team.
- Providing input to junior team members while designing an automation framework.
- Compiling of test documentation applicable to the test process.
- Managing of the defect review list and managing the defect density.

As the Test Analyst my responsibilities are as follows:

- Implemented an automated load and performance test framework to measure Quality of Service
- Security and penetration testing for PCI DSS and testing to ensure mechanisms are properly implemented for Administration and Gaming Sites
- PCI DSS basic in-house training for PCI compliance
- Responsible for for complex functional and non-functional testing of payment systems and adminstration systems
- Proof of concept to motivate automated testing tools
- Responsible for backend testing of XML APIS, SOAPUI and IMeter
- Preparing of risk register for management
- Defect tracking and investigation.
- Performing test closer activities
- Compiling pre- deployment and post-deployment documentation

Name of Company : Clickthinking Online

Type of Company : Web development and Opensource

Role : Junior PHP Developer

Period : 01 February 2007 - 31 July 2007

Product Build : Software development

- Developing and maintaining front-end interfaces
- Developing content management systems
- Planning and relational database design
- Planning and designing of front-end interfaces
- Maintaining existing websites in legacy ASP and PHP
- Responsible for functional testing unit testing of admin systems
- Managing website deployments

Name of Company : Application Frameworks

Type of Company : Web development and Open source

Role : Junior C# Developer

Period: 01 April 2005 - 31 January 2007

Product Build : Software development

Presentation layer maintenance in C#, ASP.NET

- Testing of SOAP Web-services
- Unit testing

KA 081 2019

Software test technician

Name of Company : CRSS Point Of Sale

Type of Company : Software development for hospitality systems

Role : Software Test Technician

Period : 01 February 2003 - 31 March 2005

Product Build : Software development

- Installation Point Of Sale Systems
- Functional, system & unit testing
- Testing of front end and backend systems.
- Testing of peripheral devices and device communication.
- Software development in Visual Basic 6

Technical Skills Matrix					
Skill	Years	Last Used			
	Experience				
Java	2	2020			
XML	5	2018			
XPath	1	2018			
SQL	10	2018			
UML	3	2017			
Javascript	2	2015			
VB Script	3	2019			
JSON	2	2019			
Process Modelling	2	2018			
Data Modelling	5	2017			
COBOL	Training only	2013			
C Sharp	3	2017			
PHP	1	2007			
Quality Center	3	2019			
Test Manager	1	2015			
Team Foundation Server	2	2017			
Jira	4	2019			
Eclipse IDE	1	2019			
MS VS Studio	4	2018			

CAREER INTENTIONS

I aspire to furthering my career in information technology and the software industry and researching the Internet Of Things.

CHARACTER REFERENCE

I am a creative thinker with a love for technology, self - motivated and passionate about what I do. I have a growth mindset and continuously looking to develop and utilize my skillset and continue to grow with any organization. I am always seeking to improve my knowledge by studying part time or attending courses.

REFERENCES			
CRSS Point of Sale	Manager	Miss Marriette	083 694 1304

KA 081 2019

Application Frameworks	Project Manager	Mr. Sardine Raad	
Clickthinking Online	Technical	David Murray	083 759 7724
	Manager		
ECash Systems	Test Director	Wesley Pillay	073 852 5009
ECash Systems	BA Lead	Brett Button	083 778 6960
CSG International	Manager	Janine Davids	073 167 8437
Sanlam Investments	IT Manager	Rushda McKenzie	
Capfin	Test Director	Wesley Pillay	073 852 5009
Ipreo	Product	Jonathan Greener	
	Manager		